字幕校正：Stasia
主演：布鲁斯.威利
你不喜欢飞行，是吗？
You don't like flying, do you?
吴义能教学资料之演讲篇
选自电影《虎胆龙威》（Die Hard-1988）
Ladies and gentlemen.
各位先生，女士
Ladies and gentlemen!
I want to congratulate
each and every one of you...
我要恭喜各位
这是长富公司历史性的一刻
for making this
one of the greatest years...
in the history
of the Nakatomi Corporation.
[Applause]
On behalf of
the chief executive officer,
由于这项非同凡响的成就
Mr. Ozu,
and the board of directors,
我代表董事局多谢大家
we wish you
a Merry Christmas...
并祝福大家圣诞快乐
新年快乐
and a Happy New Year!
[Crowd]
Merry Christmas!
Happy New Year!
荷莉，一起去吃晚餐好吗？
Hey, Holly,
what about
dinner tonight, huh?
Harry, it's Christmas Eve.
哈利，现在是平安夜
Families, stockings...
家人，长袜…
粟子
chestnuts...
鲁道夫和佛斯帝
Rudolph and Frosty.
Any of these things
ring a bell?
这些事是否令你想起什么？
事实上，是想起了红酒和乳酪
Actually, I was
thinking more...
of mulled wine,
a nice aged brie,
and a roaring fireplace.
躺在火盆旁聊天
明白我在说什么吗？
You know what I'm saying?
已经五点四十分了
Ginny, it's 5:40.
去喝香槟参加舞会吧
Go join the party.
Have some champagne.
你使我觉得像在压榨工人
You're making me feel
like Ebenezer Scrooge.
谢谢，麦克连太太
小朋友受得这些酒吗？
Can the baby
handle a little sip?
这个小孩已准备做酒保了
That baby's ready
to tend bar.
最后一次机会了
Last chance.
再见
Bye.
麦克连公馆，我是露西.麦克连
McClane residence.
Lucy McClane speaking.
哈，露西.麦克连
Hello, Lucy McClane.
This is
your mother speaking.
我是妈妈
Mommy!
妈，何时回家？
When are you
coming home?
很快了，很快了
Pretty soon.
不过我回来时你要在床上
You'll be in bed
when I get there, though.
让我和波莉谈一谈，好吗？
Let me talk to Paulina.
不要在屋里四处找礼物
And no snooping
around the house,
looking for presents.
爸爸和你一起回家吗？
Is Daddy coming home
with you?
到时再看看圣诞老人
和妈妈好了
Well, we'll see what...
Santa and Mommy
can do, okay?
叫波莉来，再见
Put Paulina on.
Bye, honey.
波莉
Paulina!
太太，你好
Hola, Mrs. Holly.
麦克连先生有没有打电话来？
Um, did Mr. McClane call?
没有，太太，没有打来
No, Mrs. Holly.
No telefono.
Well, he probably just
didn't have time...
或者是赶飞机来不及
before his flight.
把客房准备好以防万一
Um, make up
the spare bedroom...
just in case.
知道，荷莉小姐
我已经准备好了
Si, Mrs. Holly.
I do that already.
没有你我也不知怎算好？波莉
What would I do
without you, Paulina?
Oh!
加州
California.
Hey, I'm John McClane.
我是麦克连
Argyle.
艾加，我是司机
I'm your limo driver.
Nice bear.
这只熊仔很漂亮
好吧，现在要做些什么？
Okay... Argyle.
What do we do now?
本来希望你告诉我
You tell me.
这是我第一次驾驶大房车
It's my first time
driving a limo.
没关系，这也是我第一次坐
This is my first time
riding in one.
放心，这辆车里面什么都有
Relax. We got everything
in this mug, man.
你看CD，CB，电视，电话
Look at this...
CD, CB, TV,
telephone, full bar, VHS.
酒吧，录影机
[Laughs]
若你朋友春心动又无聊的话
我还认识些“雌熊”能陪我们
If your friend's
hot to trot,
I know a few
mama bears.
Or is he married?
他已婚了
他结婚了
He's married.
好吧
Okay.
Oh, sorry about that.
对不起，工人放了假
It's the girl's day off.
I didn't know
you were gonna sit up front.
我不知道你会坐车头前座
你太太住这里？    六个月了
So, uh, your lady
live out here?
About the past
six months.
这表示你还住在纽约？
Meaning you still
live in New York?
艾加
你常常都这么多问题吗？
You always ask
this many questions, Argyle?
对不起，我以前是驾的士的
Sorry, man.
I used to drive a cab.
客人喜欢闲聊
People would expect
a little chitchat.
So you divorced?
你离婚了？
Just drive the car, man.
开你自己的车    别这样！
离婚还是分居？
Come on.
You divorced?
还是被她打？
You separated?
She beat you up?
[Laughing]
She had a good job.
她有份好工作，变成了好事业
It turned into
a great career.
即是她要搬来这里？
That meant
she had to move here.
你反应很快啊！
You're very fast, Argyle.
那么你为什么不来呢？
So why didn't you come?
你为什么不来呢？为什么？
Well?
What's up?
Because I'm
a New York cop.
我是纽约警察
案件积压了六个月
I got a six-month backlog
of New York scumbags.
还要去捉很多人
I can't just pick up
and go that easy.
不是呼之则来
换句话说
以为她在这里不会成功
You thought
she wouldn't make it out here,
会再返回你身边
为什么收拾行李？
so why bother
to pack, right?
Like I said,
you're very fast, Argyle.
我说过，你反应真的很快
艾加
You mind if we
hear some tunes?
听点音乐好吗？
∮∮ [Funky R&B Intro]
这才对！
Hey, that will work.
Don't you got
any Christmas music?
你有圣诞歌吗？
这些就是圣诞音乐
This is Christmas music.
∮It was December 24th
on Hollis Ave. after dark ∮
∮ When I seen a man chillin'
with his dog in the park ∮
∮I approached them
very slowly ∮
∮ With my heart full of fear
looked at his dog ∮
∮ Oh, my God,
a ill reindeer ∮
∮But then I was illin'
'cause the man had a beard ∮
∮And a bag full of goodies
12:00 hit, man ∮
∮So I turned my head a second ∮
∮And the man was gone ∮
∮But he must have
dropped his wallet ∮
∮Smack dead on the lawn ∮
导演：约翰.麦特曼
∮I picked the wallet up,
and then I took a pause ∮
∮ Took out the
license and it cold said "Santa Claus"∮
∮A million dollars in it
cold hundreds of G's ∮∮
所以当你太太见到你时
So your lady sees you,
the music comes up,
大家拥抱
音乐奏起，从此快乐过一生
and you live happily
ever after, right?
这个我可以忍受
I can live with that.
If it doesn't work out,
you got a place to stay?
行不通的话，有地方住吗？
我会找个地方的
I'll find a place.
不如这样
Tell you what.
I'll wait
in the parking garage.
我去停车场等一下
成功了就致电到车上的电话
You score, you call
on the car phone.
You strike out,
I'll get you a hotel.
我就回去
失败了我就送你去酒店
You're all right, Argyle.
你真尽责，艾加
给小费时别忘了这一点
Just remember that
when you sign for the tip.
Hi.
晚安，我找荷莉.麦克连
Good evening.
I'm here to see
Holly McClane.
在那边查询
Just type it in there.
很可爱的玩具    对
Cute toy.
If you have to
take a leak,
连要去小便
它也会帮你找拉链
it finds
your zipper.
基督呀！
Christ.
30th floor.
三十楼，在宴会中
The party.
整栋楼只剩下他们
They're the only ones
left in the building.
请坐高速电梯
听到嘈杂声便出电梯
Take the express elevator...
until you hear the noise.
谢谢
Thanks.
[Whistles "Jingle Bells"]
[Crowd Noise]
Champagne, sir?
喝香槟吗？
谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
圣诞快乐
Hey, Merry Christmas!
天啊，他妈的什么鬼加州
Jesus.
Fuckin' California.
Why don't
I talk to him right now?
Hi.
我在找…荷莉.吉奈尔    对
I'm looking for...
Holly Gennero.
Yeah.
你一定是约翰麦克连
You must be
John McClane.
我是乔.高木，旅途愉快吗？
Joe Takagi.
很好
How was your ride in?
应该多谢你吗？
I have you to thank?
这是我应该做的
Seemed the least
we could do.
这地方很漂亮
将会，如果装修完毕
Quite a place
you have here.
还有许多楼正在盖建
It will be.
Several floors are
under construction.
荷莉去传真一些文件
Holly went to fax
some documents.
应立即回来
In the meanwhile,
在此同时，她的办公室在这里
her office is
right back here.
- [Sniff]
- Ellis.
艾里斯
[Sniff]
I was just making a call.
我正想打电话…
见过约翰.麦克连
I want you to meet
John McClane,
荷莉的丈夫
Holly's husband...
Holly's policeman.
荷莉的警察
Ellis is in charge of
international development.
他负责国际开发部
Heard a heck of a lot
about you.
我常听到你的名字
Missed some.
没有抹干净
[Sniff]
要我拿什么给你吗？
Can I get you anything?
食物？蛋糕？
Food? Cake?
一些加水的香槟？
Some watered-down
champagne?
不用，谢谢，我还好
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
You throw quite a party.
好盛大的派对
I didn't realize...
我不知道日本也庆祝圣诞节
they celebrated
Christmas in Japan.
这是可以调校的
Pearl Harbor
didn't work out,
珍珠没有成功！现在改用胶带
so we got you
with tape decks.
Actually, it's sort of
a double celebration.
事实上是双喜临门
今天接了一单大生意
Holly helped us close
a big deal today.
荷莉是大功臣，对不对？乔
I'll be out in
a couple of minutes.
John.
约翰
Have you met everyone?
和大家见过面了吗？
我们正在讽刺他    当然不是
We've been
sticking him with spears.
Of course, he has.
她天生是干这行的，绝顶高手
She was made
for the business.
Tough as nails.
我本来希望你能赶上那班飞机
I was hoping...
you made that flight.
给他看那个表
Show him the watch.
等一会！
Later.
Go on.
Show him.
给他看，你不好意思吗？
What, are you
embarrassed?
只是为了她努力工作的
一点奖励
A token of appreciation
for her hard work.
It's a Rolex.
是劳力士
I'm sure
I'll see it later.
我相信我等一会就会看到
Is there a place
where I could wash up?
这里有地方可以梳洗一下吗？
当然有
Sure.
你要原谅艾力
他每年这个时候就会很嘴丧
Ellis gets very depressed...
this time of year.
He thought he was
God's greatest gift.
他以为他才是上帝的恩宠
Yeah.
I know the type.
我明白这种人
Think he's got
his eye on you.
我想他看中你了
That's okay...
没关系，我看中他的私人浴室
I have my eye...
on his private bathroom.
你要住在那里？事情太过突然
Where you staying?
Things happened so fast,
来不及在电话中问你
I didn't get
a chance to ask you.
凯比.罗伯在这里退休的
Cappy Roberts
retired out here.
He told me
I could bunk with him.
是吗？
他说我可以和他一起住
凯比退休了？
Cappy retired, huh?
Where's he live?
他住那里？    罗蒙纳！
Ramona.
普蒙那
[Laughs]
Pomona.
Huh?
普蒙那    普蒙那    对
Pomona.
Yeah.
[Laughs]
你要花大半时间去坐车
You'll be in the car
half the time.
为什么不简单一点
Why don't we make it easy?
我还有空房间，面积不太大…
I have a spare bedroom.
It's not huge
or anything, but...
孩子喜欢爸爸在家
the kids would love
to have you at the house.
They would, huh?
他们会喜欢？
I would, too.
我也愿意
[Laughing]
Ooh!
对不起
Sorry.
I missed you.
我很想念你
你大概不挂念我的名字
I guess you didn't
miss my name, though, huh?
Except maybe when
you're signing checks?
或者在签支票时例外
你几时用
吉奈尔小姐的名字了？
Since when are you
"Ms. Gennero"?
这是日本人的公司
This is
a Japanese company.
- They figure
a married woman's got...
- You are a married woman.
他们认为结过婚的人…
你是已婚妇人，你嫁给我了
我们又要再讨论这个吗？
- You're married to me.
- Are we going to have
this conversation again?
七月讨论过了
我们每次都争论不出结果来
- We never finished
this conversation in July.
- I had an opportunity...
我有个机会，我必需去把握
- I had to take it.
- Right, no matter
what the consequences.
不论结果如何
不论对婚姻如何
对婚姻没有影响
- No matter what it did
to our marriage.
- It didn't do anything...
或者改变了你对婚姻的观点
except change your idea
of what our marriage should be.
我想你完全不知我对…
- You don't have a clue what my
idea of our marriage should be.
- I know exactly...
我完全知道
你所谓的婚姻是什么…
what your idea
of our marriage should be.
吉小姐
Ms. Gennero, l...
对不起
Excuse me.
Hi.
高木先生在找你
Um, Mr. Takagi
is looking for you.
他要你对下属说几句话
He wants you
to say something to the troops.
谢谢
Speech time.
演讲时间，立即回来
Be back in
a few minutes.
That was great, John.
真是太好了，约翰
做得好，太成熟了
Good job.
Very mature.
是贾巴的蓝板球，对不对？
So Kareem rebounds, right?
渥瑟是空挡，传给A.C
Feeds Worthy on the break,
再传给魔术手庄信
再交回给渥瑟
over to A.C., to Magic,
then back to Worthy, right?
两分
Boom!
Two points!
我们进来了
We're in.
∮∮ [Humming]
∮ La da da da
da da daaa! ∮
∮ Da da daaa! ∮∮
Ha ha ha!
[Buzz]
Links...
rechts...
und wieder links.
Son of a bitch.
死人头
[Laughs]
Fists with your toes.
把脚指头卷成拳头状
艾加    上面进行得怎样？
Yeah, Argyle?
How's it going up there?
尚算顺利！你在哪里
All right.
Where are you?
我在车房，与老婆谈得怎样？
What's the word with
you and your lady?
还没成定局
Uh, the vote's
not in yet.
[Speaking German]
Nein! Nein! Nein!
艾加！
麦克连！你还在吗？
Argyle?
Mac, you there?
哈？
Hello?
∮Somebody... ∮∮
你知道电话号码，用它呀！
You know the number.
Use it.
[Automatic Gunfire]
[Screaming]
[Gunshots]
[Woman Screaming]
[Screaming, Crying]
[Speaking German]
[Gunfire Continues]
- [Women Screaming]
- [Gunfire Continues]
保持冷静，一切都不会有事的
Stay calm.
Everything's going to be fine.
一切都不会有事的
该死
Shit!
用脑想！用脑想！
Think. Think.
[Screaming Continues]
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen.
各位女士，先生们
对于长富集团
对全世界的一种贪念
Due to the
Nakatomi Corporation's...
legacy of greed
around the globe,
他们将会亲眼见到
they're about to be
taught a lesson...
一种真正权力的教训
in the real use of power.
你们全部是目击证人
You will be witnesses.
现在…
Now...
Where is Mr. Takagi?
请问谁是高木先生？
高木先生
一九三七年京都出生
Joseph Yoshinobu Takagi,
- Born Kyoto, 1937.
- [Whispers] Don't move.
不要动
全家一九三九年
Family emigrated to
San Pedro, California, 1939.
移民到圣派德罗，加州
一九四二年至四三年入美籍
Interned at Manzanar,
1942 to 1943.
Scholarship student,
University of California,
一九五五年时
是加州大学奖学金学生
1955.
一九六二年
Law degree,
Stanford, 1962.
得到史丹佛大学法律学位
一九七零年哈佛商业管理博士
MBA, Harvard, 1970.
长富贸易公司董事长
President,
Nakatomi Trading.
长富投资集团副主席
Vice chairman,
Nakatomi Investment Group.
够了
Enough.
也是五个小孩的爸爸…
And father of five.
我就是高木
I am Takagi.
How do you do?
你好，很高兴认识你
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
[Groans, Cries]
好，三十二楼在装修
三十三楼电脑室
Okay, 32, construction,
33, computers.
∮∮[Humming
Beethoven's "Ode toJoy"]
∮Do de do do do ∮
∮ Do do do do
do do do de do do ∮∮
Nice suit.
漂亮的西装！
John Phillips,
London.
约翰.菲利普西装公司，伦敦
我自己也有二套
I have two myself.
传闻亦影响到阿拉法特
Rumor has it
Arafat buys his there.
[Speaking German]
推去左边
On the left.
[Speaking Italian]
（导向飞弹）
∮ Ba da da da ∮
∮ Ba da da ∮∮
"And when Alexander saw
the breadth of his domain,
当亚历山大大帝
看到他辽阔的领土时
他流泪了
因为已没有更多可以再讨伐了
he wept, for there were
no more worlds to conquer."
[Chuckling]
这是学习历史的好处
Benefits of
a classical education.
真是很漂亮
Oh,
that's beautiful.
I always enjoyed
to make models...
我小时候很喜欢砌模型
when I was a boy.
要很细心
每一个细节都要全神贯注
The exactness,
the attention to every
conceivable detail.
It's beautiful.
太美了
就是为了这个吗？
Is this what this is all about?
Our project in Indonesia?
我们在印尼的计划吗？
Contrary to what
you people may think,
正好和市民所想的相反
我们是要开发那个地区
we're going to
develop that region,
不是毁灭      我相信你
not exploit it.
I believe you.
我看过“福布斯”杂志的报导
I read the article
in Forbes.
高木先生
Mr. Takagi,
我可以和你谈一整日的
I could talk about industrialization
and men's fashions all day,
工业化和男士服装
但我一定要先将工作做完
but I'm afraid
work must intrude,
我朋友有几个问题想问你
and my associate here
has some questions for you.
Sort of fill-in-the-blanks
questions, actually.
其实有点类似填充题
[Beeping]
我没有这个密码
I don't have that code!
You broke in here
to access our computer?
你们闯进来
是要打开我们的电脑
你所得到的任何情报
Any information you could get,
when they wake up in Tokyo,
they'll change it.
等东京到了早上时就会更改
你们将无法勒索总裁
You won't be able to blackmail
our executives, threaten our pro...
坐下来
Sit... down!
高木先生
我对你的电脑没有兴趣
Mr. Takagi,
I'm really not interested...
in your computer.
但我需要密码
But I need the code key...
because I am interested
in the $640 million...
因为我对你放在保险库六亿多
in negotiable bearer bonds...
没有注上名字的股票有兴趣
that you have
locked in your vault.
And the computer
controls the vault.
金库是由电脑控制的
你只要钱？
You want money?
What kind
of terrorists are you?
你们是那一种恐怖份子？
[Chuckling]
谁说我们是恐怖份子？
Who said
we were terrorists?
The bonds represent
at most ten days'...
operating capital
for your parent organization.
请讲出密码？
The code, please.
那对你们没有用
It's useless to you.
There are seven vault safeguards,
and the code key's only one of them.
这里共有七个保安密码
只有其中一个密码
你们绝对不可能打开它
You'll never get it open.
那就没有理由不告诉我们了
Then there's no reason
not to tell us.
我已告诉过你
I told you.
还没有完成？
It's not over yet.
高木先生，你这套西装很好看
It's a very nice suit...
Mr. Takagi.
毁了它实在太可惜
It would be a shame
to ruin it.
我只会数到三
I'm going to
count to three.
不会有第四
There will not be a four.
将密码告诉我
Give me...
the code.
一…
One...
二…
Two...
三    我不知道，我告诉你
- Three.
- I don't know it. I'm telling you!
Get on the jet to Tokyo
and ask the chairman.
去问东京的董事长
我若告诉了你，你只会杀了我
I'm telling you.
You're just gonna have to kill me.
好吧
Okay.
We'll do it
the hard way.
我们唯有用辛苦一点的
办法解决吧
东尼你搅定这个
Tony, see if you
can dispose of that.
卡尔
你去机房看一下海奈的进度
Karl, better check
on Heinrich's work.
[Grunting]
没有人！
Nothing.
去看看海奈
See to Heinrich.
现在…
Now...
you can
break the code?
你可以破解密码吗？
你不是因我迷人的个性
而带我来
You didn't
bring me along...
for my charming
personality.
艾加，告诉我你也听到枪声
Argyle, tell me
you heard the shots.
立即报警
You're callin'
the police right now.
我等一会当然仍会过去
∮∮[Loud Music]
Of course
I'm coming by later.
我有骗过你吗？
Have I ever lied to you?
我的老板？
我相信我很快会去赌城了
My boss?
Thinks I'm on my way to Vegas.
Uli, get up on the pipes.
乌利，到管道上面去
马可，你由这里过去
Marco, you go
through here.
I'll throw you the cord.
我用无线电与你联络
Hans, we're on the roof.
汉斯，我们在屋顶
这里
Here.
三十分钟就破解密码
Thirty minutes
to break the code,
两小时至两个半小时
Two hours, two and a half hours
for the five mechanicals...
至少解决五个机件方面
at the minimum.
不过第七个锁，我就无能为力
The seventh lock,
however, is out of my hands.
对不起
I'm sorry...
这七个锁，是由电磁场封住的
The seventh lock...
the electromagnetic seal.
You do understand...
这种线路不可能在这里截断
the circuits cannot
be cut locally.
相信我！
Trust me.
死人头你为什么不阻止他？
约翰
Why the fuck
didn't you stop him, John?
因为那样做你一定死梗
白痴
'Cause then
you'd be dead, too, asshole!
用脑想，该死的！用脑想
Think, goddamn it!
Think!
[Beeping]
火警钟响起了
We've got a fire alarm.
打911
Call 911.
告诉他大厦密码，护卫的姓名
Give them the guard's name
and the building code number,
将警报取消
之后毁灭整个系统
and cancel the alarm.
Then disable the system.
在那一层响起警钟的？
On what floor
did the alarm go off?
可以动手了吗？
Now, shall we go?
不能
Nein.
[Sirens]
宝贝，来找爸爸，快点
Oh, baby, come to Papa.
Come on.
[Laughing]
宝贝，来，宝贝，来找爸爸
Come on, baby.
Come to Papa.
我会去吻你的达马西亚狗
I'll kiss
your fuckin'dalmatian.
你们这些蠢蛋，不，不
You stupid motherfuckers!
No!
将这辆死车调头
Turn the fuckin' truck around!
火警已经救熄了，老友
The fire has been
called off, my friend.
No one is coming to help you.
没有人会来救你
你最好出来与其他人一起吧
You might as well
come out and join the others.
我保证不会伤害你
I promise
I won't hurt you.
[Whirring]
放低枪，是警察
Drop it, dickhead.
It's the police.
You won't hurt me.
你不会杀我
是吗？为什么不可以？
Yeah? Why not?
Because
you're a policeman.
因为你是警察
警察是不能乱来的
There are rules
for policemen.
Yeah. That's what
my captain keeps telling me.
对，我的上司也不断告诉我
定！
Aah!
无法开启要继续程式吗？
当然要继续
You bet your ass
I wish to proceed.
世界上有九百万个恐怖份子
Nine million terrorists
in the world,
我却杀了个
and I got to kill one
with feet smaller than my sister.
比我妹妹的脚还小的一个
我要这件事做得非常专业
I wanted this
to be professional,
有效率和合作
efficient, and cooperative.
要求不高
Not a lot to ask.
显然高木先生不是这种想法
Alas, Mr. Takagi
did not see it that way,
所以在他有生之年
也不会加入我们
so he won't be joining us
for the rest of his life.
你们可以随自己
喜欢的方法离开
We can go
any way you want it.
你们可以步行离开这里
或被人抬出去
You can walk out
or be carried out,
但不要有任何妄想
but have no illusions...
we are in charge.
这儿是由我们说了算
所以…现在自己去决定
- So... decide now, each of you,
- [Elevator Bell Dings]
请记住
And please remember...
我们是不靠机会的
we have left nothing
to chance.
- [Speaking German]
- [Screaming Continues]
叫他们退后
Get them back!
[Speaking German]
"Now I have
a machine gun.
现在我有机关枪了
哈，哈，哈
Ho-ho-ho. "
漏掉的护卫？
A security guard
we missed?
通常他们只会靠退休金
而变得肥肥白白
They're usually
just growing fat on a pension.
这不一样！
This is
something else.
[Speaking German]
我们一定要想个办法，汉斯
We have to do
something, Hans.
我们要！
Yes, we do.
去告诉卡尔，他弟弟死了
Tell Karl his brother is dead.
叫他下来
Tell him
to come down.
Karl...
komm sofort.
Franco, you and Fritz take
the body upstairs and out of sight.
法兰哥，你和佛列兹
将尸体搬去楼上，并收好
我不要人质认为…
I don't want the hostages
to think too much.
[Speaking German]
Aah!
我要血腥！
你会得到
I want blood!
But let Heinrich
plant the detonators.
不过先等海奈将雷管装好
The police will waste hours
trying to negotiate.
在我们报警后，他们会浪费
数小时来谈判，这样
Then you can
tear the building apart.
你便可以在整座大厦
氐姿巡檎飧鋈
但在那之前
我们不能改变计划
But until then,
do not alter the plan.
如果他更改了计划呢？
And if he alters it?
你认为如何？
[Ellis]
What do you think?
有点不妥      警察？
Something's wrong.
Cops?
约翰！              约翰…
John.
John...Aw, Christ!
He can fuck this whole thing up!
主啊！他会将整件事破坏
他以为他在做什么？
他的职责
What does
he think he's doing?
His job.
胡说八道！
他的职责在三千英里外
Bullshit. His job's
3,000 miles away.
Without him, we might
be able to get out of here.
没有他的话
我们或者还有机会
可以离开这里
去对高木说吧！
Tell that to Takagi.
救命…有人听到九号频道吗？
Mayday. Mayday,
Anyone copying channel nine.
恐怖份子占领了长富大楼
Terrorists have seized
the Nakatomi Building...
最少胁持了三十个人质
and are holding
30 hostages.
我再讲一次
Unknown number
of terrorists...
不明数目的恐怖份子
Six or more armed
with automatic weapons.
着大量武器占领长富大楼
这是由那里传送出去的？
Where's the best place
to transmit?
回答我吧！他妈的！
在屋顶
- Somebody answer me, goddamn it!
- The roof!
快去，快去
Go! Go!
火警号报发自同一地方
[Woman] It's the same
address as that fire signal.
我来处理
I'll handle it.
无论你在那里，请注意
Attention,
whoever you are,
这个频道是预留给紧急用途
this channel
is reserved for emergencies.
他妈的！小姐
[John]
No shit, lady!
我听起来像在叫比萨饼吗？
I'm not ordering
a pizza!
No one kills him
but me.
除了我之外
任何人也不准杀他
他们已经杀了一个人质
They have
killed one hostage.
现在他们已经开始了
他们的阴谋
They are fortifying
their positions...
你们还不让我用频道
while you're jerking
me off on the radio!
叫警察来
这个频道已经预留了，先生
Sir, I've
already told you.
This is
a reserved channel.
如有紧急事情
If this is
an emergency call, dial 911.
请用电话打911
否则我就要告你
Otherwise, I'll report
this as an FCC violation.
违反联邦通信法例
很好，你他妈的去告我吧！
Fine! Come and arrest me,
just send the police now!
最好派个警察来捉我，快点！
Ow!
[Yells]
看看能否联络一部警车
叫他过去看看
See if there's
a black-and-white
to do a drive-by.
∮∮ [Humming]
我以为你们只吃油炸圈饼
Thought you guys
just ate doughnuts.
They're for my wife.
这是给我太太的
Yeah.
她怀孕了      是吗？
She's pregnant.
Yeah.
包起来
Bag it.
来得及时
Big time.
[Chuckling]
谢谢
Thanks.
总台叫林肯三十号
[Woman] Dispatch
to 8-Lincoln-30. Over.
我是林肯三十号，请回答
This is 8-Lincoln-30.
Come on in. Over.
有人报案长富大楼二号有事
Investigate a Code 2...
请过去巡视一下
at Nakatomi Plaza,
Century City.
林肯三十号回答总台
8-Lincoln-30 to dispatch.
I'm on my way.